A Guide to the Stonewall Jackson Papers 1844-1915
Virginia Military Institute Archives
- Correspondence, outgoing 1844-1863
  - Civil War, 1861-1863
    - To Revd. Francis McFarland, written at Staunton, Virginia, 1862 July 31 (Box-folder 2:54A)
    - To Margaret Junkin Preston, written at Bunker Hill, Berkeley Co., Virginia, 1862 August (Box-folder 2:54B)
    - To Francis H. Smith, written at near Gordonsville, Virginia, 1862 August 7 (Box-folder 2:54C)
    - To Gen. Trimble, written at Bristow 1862 August 27 (Box-folder 2:55)
    - To Miss Fairfield, written at Sharpsburg 1862 September 16 (Box-folder 2:56)
    - To General Cooper, written at HQ, Valley District, 1862 September 22 (Box-folder 2:57)
    - To General Cooper, written at HQ, Valley District, 1862 September 22 (Box-folder 2:57)
    - To [unknown], written at HQ, Valley District, 1862 October 15 (Box-folder 2:58)
    - To Revd. Francis McFarland, written at Clarke Co., Virginia, 1862 October 15 (Box-folder 2:59A)
    - To John T. L. Preston, written at HQ, Valley District, Virginia, 1862 November 18 (Box-folder 2:59B)
    - To Gen. Pendleton, written at [unknown] 1862 December 7 (Box-folder 2:60)
    - To Gen. D. H. Hill, written at HQ, 2nd Corps, ANV 1862 December 8 (Box-folder 2:61)
    - To Maj. Wells J. Hawks, written at HQ, 2nd Corps, ANV 1863 January 7 (Box-folder 2:62)
    - To Isabella Morrison Hill, written at Caroline Co., VA 1863 January 24 (Box-folder 2:63)
    - To Capt. Barringer, written at Corbins Farm, Caroline Co., VA 1863 February 11 (Box-folder 2:64)
    - To Gen. Chilton, written at HQ, 2nd Corps, ANV, 1863 February 11 (Box-folder 2:65)
    - To Mitchell and Tyler, written near Fredericksburg, Virginia, 1863 April 15 (Box-folder 2:66)
    - To Gen. D. H. Hill, 1863 unknown date, 7:45 a.m. (Box-folder 2:67)
    - To Major ?, date unknown (Box-folder 2:68)
- Correspondence, incoming, 1854-1863 (Box-folder 2:69-81)
  This series contains miscellaneous incoming correspondence and consists of 13 items.
- Reports, Orders, and misc. related documents, 1861-1863, 15 items (Box-folder 3:1-15)
- Financial Documents, 1853-1863 (Box-folder 3:16-25)
  This series consists primarily of VMI paychecks endorsed on reverse by Jackson. It also contains a bankshare certificate (1858) and an estate document (1863 June 5).
- Tributes and Memorials, 1863-1961 (Box-folder 3:26)
- Jackson Family Miscellaneous, 1841-1923 (Box-folder 3:27-30)
- Mary Anna Morrison Jackson Papers, 1845-1915 (Box-folder 4:1-22)
  This series consists primarily of incoming and outgoing correspondence from the post-Civil War era.
- Julia Jackson Christian, 1873-1891 (Box-folder 4:23)
  Miscellaneous documents relating to Jackson's daughter, Julia.
- Arnold Family Papers, 1847-1902 (Box-folder 5:1-19)
  This series includes correspondence to and from Laura Jackson Arnold, Stark W. Arnold, Jonathan Arnold, and others.
- Jackson-related Printed Material & misc., 1863-1899 (Box 6)
  Includes misc. pamphlets concerning the life of Jackson, sheet music dedicated to Jackson, and miscellaneous items.